<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sides on Food for Thought</title>
    <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/categories/sides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sides on Food for Thought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/categories/sides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Brussel Sprouts</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  brussel sprouts ~500g / ~1 lb 2 Tbs olive oil 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp red pepperflakes 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp garlic powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp onion powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp black pepper  Directions Preheat oven to 500 degrees, with foil&amp;rsquo;d baking sheet inside.
Rinse sprouts, cut each in half. Toss with oil and spices in large bowl.
Put sprouts on hot baking sheet, flip them fast so cut side is down and return to oven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Fries</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2lbs sweet potatoes 2 Tbs olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp paprika 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp black pepper  Directions Preheat oven to 425 degrees.
Peel potatoes if the skin bothers you. Slice potatoes in to strips 1&amp;frasl;4 inch wide.
Mix spices with oil, toss with potatoes in large bowl.
Spread fries on baking sheet; be sure to leave lots of space between and use two sheets if needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cornbread</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 boxes Jiffy cornbread muffin mix 2 eggs 1&amp;frasl;3 cup milk 1 can creamed corn 2 tbs Sugar 1 tbs butter (to grease skillet)  Directions Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Find a cast iron skillet.
Combine all ingredients in bowl. Mix and allow to sit for a few minutes.
Place the skillet in the oven for a few minutes to allow it to warm up. Take out the skillet and coat the inside with butter (or fat).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texas Trash</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 small can chopped black olives 1 small can green chiles 2 large tomatoes (diced) 4 green onions (chopped) 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp Garlic salt  Directions Mix and chill.
Serve with tortilla chips.
Notes Lately I have been adding some black pepper and using a combination of roma and regular tomatoes. You need to have juice so you can&amp;rsquo;t use all romas - I also find better to use a little more tomatoes rather than less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice Baked Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 potatoes 2 sticks of butter 1 cup Sour Cream milk (if necessary) ~2 cups Cheddar/Jack Cheese ~1&amp;frasl;2 cup Bacon Bits 5 green onions (chopped) 2 tsp Lawry’s Seasoned Salt 1 tsp garlic salt 1 tsp onion powder black pepper  Directions Bake potatoes at 400 for 1:15 or until cooked through.
Halve the potatoes and scoop out the insides, try to preserve the skins. Mix the potato innards with all of the other ingredients (using only half of the cheese).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Salad</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 eggs 3 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 &amp;amp; 1&amp;frasl;2 tablespoons prepared Dijon-style mustard 1 teaspoon dried dill weed 1 teaspoon paprika 1&amp;frasl;2 red onion, minced salt and pepper to taste  Directions Place eggs in a saucepan and cover with cold water. Bring water to a boil; cover, remove from heat, and let eggs stand in hot water for 10 to 12 minutes. Remove from hot water, cool, peel and chop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>