<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Food for Thought</title>
    <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Food for Thought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Spicy Tofu</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Tofu &amp;amp; Marinade
 1 lb firm tofu 3&amp;frasl;4 cup tamari 3&amp;frasl;4 cup dark sesame oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup sugar 1 cup cornstarch oil for frying (generally a few cups of vegetable oil)  Sweet &amp;amp; Spicy Sauce
 1&amp;frasl;4 Cup Honey 1&amp;frasl;4 Cup Sriracha (or other chili paste) 2 Tbs Sesame Oil Sesame seeds (garnish)  Directions If needed, press tofu to remove liquid.
Slice tofu in to ~3&amp;frasl;4 inch cubes and place in shallow container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focaccia</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/focaccia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/focaccia/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients For biga:
 320g bread flour (all-purpose is fine too) 1.5g [1&amp;frasl;2 tsp] instant yeast 215g water  For main dough:
 241g [2 cup] all-purpose flour 6g [2 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp] instant yeast 6g [1 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp] salt 7g [1 tsp] honey 25g [2 Tbsp] olive oil (for dough, more as topping later) 113g [1&amp;frasl;2 cup] water Toppings of your choice  Directions Day before: (15 min + 2 hrs)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesame Salmon and Green Beans</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sesame-salmon-and-green-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sesame-salmon-and-green-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2&amp;frasl;3 lb salmon 2&amp;frasl;3 lb green beans splash of oil for cooking rice  glaze:  3 Tbsp soy sauce 1 Tbsp water 2 Tbsp rice wine (mirin) 2 Tbsp brown sugar 1&amp;frasl;2 Tbsp toasted sesame oil 1 clove garlic, minced 1&amp;frasl;2 inch fresh ginger, grated (optional) 1 Tbsp sesame seeds 1 Tbsp cornstarch  Directions Make rice.
Mix all sauce ingredients in a small bowl, stir until cornstarch dissolves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Milk Bread</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Tangzhong:
 2 Tbs bread flour 2 Tbs water 4 Tbs whole milk  Bread Dough:
 320g [2.5 cups] bread flour 1 Tbs active dry yeast 3&amp;frasl;4 tsp sea salt 1&amp;frasl;2 cup whole milk 1&amp;frasl;4 cup sugar 3 Tbs unsalted butter, softened 1 egg, room temperature  Egg wash:
 one egg splash of whole milk  Directions Total time: 4-5 hours
Take egg out of fridge to warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage and Kale Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-and-kale-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-and-kale-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 package pasta, something small and squiggly (use half-package for less carbs) 2 Tbsp olive oil 12 oz. chicken sausage 2 Tbsp butter 2 cloves garlic, minced 8 oz. chopped kale (~1 bunch) 8 kalamata olives, chopped 1&amp;frasl;4 cup grated Parmesan 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp crushed red pepper  Instructions Cook pasta according to package; drop the pasta before before beginning next steps. Remember to reserve some pasta water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Brussel Sprouts</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  brussel sprouts ~500g / ~1 lb 2 Tbs olive oil 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp red pepperflakes 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp garlic powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp onion powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp black pepper  Directions Preheat oven to 500 degrees, with foil&amp;rsquo;d baking sheet inside.
Rinse sprouts, cut each in half. Toss with oil and spices in large bowl.
Put sprouts on hot baking sheet, flip them fast so cut side is down and return to oven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Bread</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/basic-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/basic-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g [3 cups] bread flour (or AP flour) 1g [1&amp;frasl;4 tsp] instant yeast 8g [1 tsp] salt 300g [1 1&amp;frasl;3 cup] water  Directions Day before: (~15 min)
Combine flour, yeast, and salt in large bowl. Add water and mix until combined, then 30sec more. Dough should be wet and sticky, and not hold shape at all.
Cover bowl with towel or wrap, and let sit at room temperature for 12-24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braised Pork Belly</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ramen Eggs  1 cup Japanese soy sauce 1 piece kombu 1&amp;frasl;2 cup mirin 1&amp;frasl;2 cup cooking sake 1&amp;frasl;2 cup bonito flakes 1&amp;frasl;4 cup sugar 8 cloves garlic crushed 8 eggs  Braised beef  1 lb pork belly or shoulder, cut to 1&amp;frasl;3 in cubes 1 Tbsp vegetable oil 2 Tbsp shaoxing wine 3 Tbsp dark soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;4 cup fried shallots/onions 1 Tbsp garlic, chopped 2 star anise 2 dried shiitake mushrooms, soaked 1 stick cinnamon 2 Tbsp rock sugar or brown sugar 2&amp;frasl;3 cup hot water 10-15 dried chiles 2 Tbsp sichuan bean paste 3 tsp sambal olek 2 tsp chili crisp oil cornstarch  Directions Ramen Egg Boil a large pot of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portobello Caps</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/portobello-caps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/portobello-caps/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 large portobello caps 1&amp;frasl;8 cup canola (or other high heat) oil 1 Tbs balsamic vinegar 1 tsp dijon mustard 4 cloves garlic 1 tsp thyme 1 tsp soy sauce black pepper   Directions Clean mushrooms, remove stems, scrape out gills. Slice if desired.
Combine all other ingredients to make marinade. Cover mushrooms and let sit for ~1hr.
Grill for ~10 minutes.
Things to try / optional additions: - 3 Tbs chopped onion - rosemary - cayenne</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Potato Fries</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2lbs sweet potatoes 2 Tbs olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp paprika 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp black pepper  Directions Preheat oven to 425 degrees.
Peel potatoes if the skin bothers you. Slice potatoes in to strips 1&amp;frasl;4 inch wide.
Mix spices with oil, toss with potatoes in large bowl.
Spread fries on baking sheet; be sure to leave lots of space between and use two sheets if needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Curry</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1-2 lb chicken 1 medium yellow onion, chopped 1 lb carrots 1.5 lb yukon gold potatoes 3 cups chicken stock (bullion works) 1 package curry cubes (~200g, I use &amp;ldquo;Golden Curry&amp;rdquo; brand) 1 Tbsp tomato paste (can use ketchup) 1 Tbsp soy sauce 3 cloves garlic  Optional additions:  1 apple, grated 1&amp;frasl;2 bar chocolate pinch of cheddar cheese 1 tablespoon honey  Directions Peel and chop potatoes in to 1&amp;frasl;2 inch cubes, put in a bowl with water to de-starch while doing next steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 lb beef stew meat 8 oz mushrooms 1 lb carrots 1.5 lb potatoes 14 oz bag frozen pearl onions 2 Tbsp flour 2 Tbsp butter 2 cups beef broth (bullion works) 1 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 Tbsp soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;2 Tbsp brown sugar 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 Tbsp tomato paste 1 tsp dried rosemary 1 tsp dried thyme Salt and pepper  Directions If stew beef is coarsely cut, further cut in to 1&amp;frasl;2-in cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Bowl Stir Fry with Peanut Sauce</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pork-bowl-stir-fry-with-peanut-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pork-bowl-stir-fry-with-peanut-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Spicy Peanut Sauce  1&amp;frasl;8 cup natural-style peanut butter 1 Tbsp sriracha 1 tsp soy sauce 1 tsp grated fresh ginger 1 tsp brown sugar 3 Tbsp hot water  Pork Mixture  1&amp;frasl;2 lb ground pork, chicken or turkey 8 oz button mushrooms 1 large carrot 1 red bell pepper 2 cloves garlic 1 tsp grated fresh ginger 1&amp;frasl;3 cup hoisin sauce 1 Tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp toasted sesame oil 1&amp;frasl;2 Tbsp neutral cooking oil  Bowl  4 cups cooked rice 1&amp;frasl;4 cup peanuts, chopped 2-3 green onions, sliced  Directions Make sauce by combining all ingredients in small bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shredded Chicken</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbsp canola, vegetable or avocado oil 2 lbs boneless skinless chicken, cubed 1&amp;frasl;2 yellow onion, thinly sliced 4 cloves garlic, minced 1 tsp chili powder 1 tsp cumin 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp coriander 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp kosher sea salt 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp oregano juice of 2 oranges juice of 2 limes 1&amp;frasl;2 jalapeño, minced (or a whole pepper if you prefer slightly spicier) 1&amp;frasl;2 c. fresh cilantro  Directions Saute chicken with a small amount of oil and garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Bulgogi</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-bulgogi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-bulgogi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.5 lb beef (flank, sirloin, or strip cuts usually) 1 large zucchini peanut oil (or similar, for cooking) 1&amp;frasl;3 cup soy sauce 3 Tbsp brown sugar 1 medium yellow onion (chopped long and thin, divided) 2 stalks green onion (chopped) 1&amp;frasl;2 asian pear (peeled and chunked) 1 Tbsp sesame oil 2 Tbsp sesame seeds 2 Tbsp minced garlic 1 Tbsp sriracha sauce 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp cayenne pepper 2 tsp Korean red pepper powder (&amp;ldquo;gochugaru&amp;rdquo;) black pepper  Instructions  Slice beef in to long thin strips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients For the Chicken:
 1&amp;frasl;2 cup whole milk yogurt 1.5 tsp salt 1 tsp turmeric 1 tsp garam masala (okay to substitute curry powder) 1 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp ground cumin 2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 2-inch chunks  For the Sauce:
 4 tablespoons unsalted butter 1 medium yellow onion, finely chopped 1 tablespoon finely chopped fresh ginger 1.25 tsp garam masala (okay to substitute curry powder) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp Scampi</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 lb shrimp 1&amp;frasl;3 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup cold butter cut into 1 Tbsp chunks 1&amp;frasl;2 cup white wine (pinot) 2 Tbsp garlic 2 tsp red pepper flakes 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp baking soda 2 Tbsp lemon juice 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chopped fresh parsley salt and pepper pasta french bread, sliced thin  Directions Thaw and peel your shrimp, then dry them well with paper towels. Put in a sealable bowl and toss with 1 tspn salt and 1&amp;frasl;4 tspn baking soda for 15 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/oatmeal-chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/oatmeal-chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1&amp;frasl;2 cup butter, softened 1&amp;frasl;2 cup packed light brown sugar 1&amp;frasl;4 cup white sugar 1 eggs 1 teaspoons vanilla extract 5&amp;frasl;8 cups all-purpose flour 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon baking soda 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon salt 1.5 cups quick-cooking oats 1&amp;frasl;3 cup chopped walnuts/pecans 1&amp;frasl;3 cup semisweet chocolate chips 1&amp;frasl;4 cup white chocolate chips  Directions Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F (165 degrees C).
In a large bowl, cream together the butter, brown sugar, and white sugar until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Tomato Cream Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 pack sausage (chicken and apple sausage works well) 1 package mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chicken stock (bullion water) 1 package noodles 1 big can tomatoes in sauce 0.5-1 cup heavy cream 1&amp;frasl;4 cup parmesan cheese olive oil butter 1 onion garlic  Spices:
 basil oregano parsley garlic powder rosemary thyme red pepper flakes cayenne powder  Directions Boil water for noodles.
Slice sausage and chop onion, saute in oil in very large pan until browned and happy looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat Sauce</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 pounds ground beef (I used ground round) 2 pounds sausage 3 tablespoons olive oil 2 large yellow onions, diced 2 green bell peppers, seeded and diced 3 cups fresh mushrooms, chopped 6 cloves garlic, minced 1 cup white wine or stock (your choice) Two 28-ounce cans crushed tomatoes One 24-ounce jar good store-bought marinara sauce One 6-ounce can tomato paste 2 tablespoons sugar 2 teaspoons kosher salt 2 teaspoon ground oregano 2 teaspoon ground thyme 2 teaspoon dried rosemary 3 teaspoon crushed red pepper, optional 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon cayenne, optional 5 bay leaves 1&amp;frasl;4 cup finely minced fresh parsley or 3 tablespoons parsley flakes (plus a little more for serving) 1 whole rind from 1 wedge Parmesan, optional 1&amp;frasl;2 cup grated Parmesan, optional (plus more for serving)  Makes a lot of sauce, you might want to halve it or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley Soup</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/barley-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/barley-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 qts water 2 ham hocks 1&amp;frasl;4 cup split peas 3&amp;frasl;4 cup barley 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chopped onion 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chopped celery 2-3 potatoes, cubed  Instructions Cook ham hocks in water for 2 hours (note: may be too long for smallish ham hocks, maybe try less) Add barley, split peas, celery and onion, simmer 2.5 - 3 hours. Remove ham from hocks, trim off fat. Return meat to pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant Parmesan</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/eggplant-parmesean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/eggplant-parmesean/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 Tbsp butter 2 c chopped onion (or oil works) 3 clove garlic, mashed 2 lb ground chuck 3 cans tomato sauce (8 oz) 4 tsp dried oregano leaves 2 tsp dried basil leaves 3&amp;frasl;4 tsp anise seed 2 large eggplant 2 eggs, slightly beaten 1 1&amp;frasl;2 c dried bread crumbs 1&amp;frasl;2 c grated Parmesan cheese 2 c vegetable or olive oil 1 c mozzarella cheese  Directions In a skillet melt butter/oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cornbread</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 boxes Jiffy cornbread muffin mix 2 eggs 1&amp;frasl;3 cup milk 1 can creamed corn 2 tbs Sugar 1 tbs butter (to grease skillet)  Directions Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Find a cast iron skillet.
Combine all ingredients in bowl. Mix and allow to sit for a few minutes.
Place the skillet in the oven for a few minutes to allow it to warm up. Take out the skillet and coat the inside with butter (or fat).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice Bowl with Chinese sausage</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rice-bowl-with-chinese-sausage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rice-bowl-with-chinese-sausage/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups (rice cooker cups) white rice 2 cups broccoli ~2 cups chicken stock (amount depends on rice cooker) 1&amp;frasl;2 package Chinese sausage (maybe 1&amp;frasl;2 lb ish?) 2 cups frozen mixed veggies (peas/corn/carrots/etc) 1&amp;frasl;3 cup crushed pineapple 2.5 Tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp sesame oil 3 tbs sriracha other spices as desired  Directions Rinse and cut broccoli.
Begin cooking rice the usual way (rinse it, you fool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosemary Chicken and Mushroom Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 large boneless skinless chicken breasts 4 tbs butter, divided 1 tbs olive oil 10 oz package baby portabella mushrooms 1 clove garlic, minced 1.5 cup chicken stock 1 tsp crushed rosemary (or 1 large bruised sprig fresh) 1 tsp oregano 1 tsp thyme 1&amp;frasl;2 cup heavy cream (use less if you want to live past 50) pasta noodles of your choice  Seasoned Flour:
 1 cup flour 2 tsp salt 1 tsp pepper 2 tsp garlic powder  Instructions  Slice chicken in to thin strips roughly 2&amp;rdquo;x1&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Bean Chicken Quesadillas</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/black-bean-chicken-quesadillas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/black-bean-chicken-quesadillas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1&amp;frasl;2 lb, chicken tenderloin 1 (15 oz.) can black beans 1 cup frozen corn kernels 1&amp;frasl;2 small red onion, diced 1 clove garlic, minced 1&amp;frasl;2 bunch fresh cilantro, chopped 2 cups shredded cheese 1 (~2 Tbs) batch taco seasoning (try chili powder and cayenne) 10 taco sized tortillas fresh squeezed lime (to taste) oil to cook  Instructions Cook chicken with some garlic and oil. Chop up everything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Toast</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon ground nutmeg 2 tablespoons sugar 4 tablespoons butter 3 eggs 1&amp;frasl;4 cup milk 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon vanilla extract 8 slices challah, brioche, or white bread 1&amp;frasl;2 cup maple syrup, warmed  Directions In a small bowl, combine, cinnamon, nutmeg, and sugar and set aside briefly.
In a 10-inch or 12-inch skillet, melt butter over medium heat. Whisk together cinnamon mixture, eggs, milk, and vanilla and pour into a shallow container such as a pie plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texas Trash</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 small can chopped black olives 1 small can green chiles 2 large tomatoes (diced) 4 green onions (chopped) 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp Garlic salt  Directions Mix and chill.
Serve with tortilla chips.
Notes Lately I have been adding some black pepper and using a combination of roma and regular tomatoes. You need to have juice so you can&amp;rsquo;t use all romas - I also find better to use a little more tomatoes rather than less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice Baked Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 potatoes 2 sticks of butter 1 cup Sour Cream milk (if necessary) ~2 cups Cheddar/Jack Cheese ~1&amp;frasl;2 cup Bacon Bits 5 green onions (chopped) 2 tsp Lawry’s Seasoned Salt 1 tsp garlic salt 1 tsp onion powder black pepper  Directions Bake potatoes at 400 for 1:15 or until cooked through.
Halve the potatoes and scoop out the insides, try to preserve the skins. Mix the potato innards with all of the other ingredients (using only half of the cheese).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiced Apple Cider</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/apple-cider/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/apple-cider/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1&amp;frasl;2 gal apple cider 1&amp;frasl;2 cup pineapple juice 1&amp;frasl;2 fresh orange, sliced (with peel) 2 tsp lemon juice 3 cinnamon sticks 1.5 tsp whole cloves 1&amp;frasl;2 of a nutmeg, ground/smashed (or 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp nutmeg powder)  Ingredients Combine all ingredients and heat. The spices will get stronger over the next few hours, I suggest waiting at least 2 hours to drink. Strain it out to pour in to cups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stir Fry with Chicken and Broccoli</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups broccoli florets (frozen steam broccoli works, follow bag directions) ~2 cups stir fry veggie mix -&amp;gt; sugar peas, mushrooms, peppers? (if you can find a frozen one just chuck it in frozen) 1 tablespoon olive oil 2 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves - cut into 1 inch strips 1&amp;frasl;4 cup sliced green onions 4 cloves garlic, thinly sliced 1 tablespoon hoisin sauce 1 tablespoon chile paste (sriracha works!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac n Cheese</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tbsp butter 2 tbsp flout 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 2 cups milk 2 cups shredded white sharp cheddar cheese, divided 2 cups elbow macaroni, cooked and drained bread crumbs  Instructions  Preheat oven to 350 F
 Melt butter in saucepan on low heat, add flour and salt, mix well. Cook 2 minutes or until bubbly. Gradually add milk, stirring until well blended. Cook on medium heat until mixture boils and thickens, stirring constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chili/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.5 lbs ground beef 1&amp;frasl;2 lbs chorizo sausage (not in casing) 1 large yellow onion, diced 4 cloves garlic, minced 1 15oz can black beans (strain out ~half the juice) 1 15oz can kidney beans (strain out ~half the juice) 1 14oz can diced tomatoes (dump entire can) 1 14oz can stewed tomatoes (dump entire can) 2 jalapenos, seeded and diced 1&amp;frasl;2 bottle of beer (IPA works great) 2 shots whiskey 3 Tbsp chili powder 1+ teaspoons cayenne 1 Tbsp cumin black pepper  Note: I often make a double batch of this recipe, which ends up being about 12 bowls of chili.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Shrimp Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Shrimp and pasta  1 pound raw peeled and deveined shrimp 1&amp;frasl;4 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;8 cup parmesan cheese 4 garlic cloves, minced 2 teaspoons brown sugar 2 teaspoons soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon red pepper flakes 1 package pasta (linguine are my favorite) sliced green onion (garnish)  Cream sauce:  1 cup heavy cream 3 Tbsp butter 2 Tbsp parmesan cheese red pepper flakes cayenne pepper salt and pepper  Instructions In a bowl, whisk olive oil, parmesan, brown sugar, soy sauce, garlic and red pepper flakes together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Couscous</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-and-couscous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-and-couscous/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons olive oil 2 cups onion, diced 2 cups celery, diced 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 1&amp;frasl;3 cups Israeli (Pearl) Couscous 2 cups chicken broth 1 lb chicken, chopped salt and pepper  Directions Cook chicken.
In a large skillet, heat olive oil over medium high heat. Add onion, carrots, and celery, season with salt and pepper, and saute for 5-10 minutes until softened and caramelized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Tea</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-tea/</guid>
      <description>Makes 1 Gallon
Ingredients  2.25 cups sugar 1&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon baking soda 1 gallon filtered water 12 tea bags (I use plain Lipton bags)   Directions Add baking soda to 4 cups of water, boil
Remove from heat, add tea bags to boiled water and steep for 15 min, remove without squeezing
Stir in sugar until dissolved
Add remaining water</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peppermint Bark</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/peppermint-bark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/peppermint-bark/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  10 ounces dark chocolate (morsels work great) 10 ounces white chocolate (morsels work great) 2 teaspoons vegetable oil (flavorless oil) 4 candy cane&amp;rsquo;s worth of ground up candy canes (Peppermints probably also work)  Instructions Line a cookie sheet with aluminum foil. This recipe makes about the right amount for about half of a standard baking sheet. Consider a double recipe.
Melt dark chocolate with 1 tsp vegetable oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Salad</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 eggs 3 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 &amp;amp; 1&amp;frasl;2 tablespoons prepared Dijon-style mustard 1 teaspoon dried dill weed 1 teaspoon paprika 1&amp;frasl;2 red onion, minced salt and pepper to taste  Directions Place eggs in a saucepan and cover with cold water. Bring water to a boil; cover, remove from heat, and let eggs stand in hot water for 10 to 12 minutes. Remove from hot water, cool, peel and chop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesto</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups fresh basil leaves (lightly packed before cutting) 1&amp;frasl;2 cup fresh parsley (lightly packed before cutting) 3 cloves garlic 1&amp;frasl;2 cup grated Parmesan cheese 3&amp;frasl;4 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup pine nuts  Directions Chop everything up super fine, with a processor if you have one, or by hand if you&amp;rsquo;re up to a challenge. Combine all.
Serving suggestions: Serve with garlic-sauteed chicken over cavatappi pasta and a glass of mid-tier wine while watching Battlestar Galactica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/drinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/drinks/</guid>
      <description>1 JAGER BOMB boil 1 cup red bull (in place of water), add black cherry or orange jello, 1 cups jager.
2 MARGARITA boil 1 cup water, add 3 oz pkg lime jello, 4 oz tequila, 4 oz sweet &amp;amp; sour margarita mix. sprinkle with salt just before firm. (substitue watermelon jello for lime for a melon margarita)
3 *RUM &amp;amp; COKE boil 1 cups coke, mix in dark cherry jello add 1 cups light rum</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>