<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pasta on Food for Thought</title>
    <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/categories/pasta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pasta on Food for Thought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/categories/pasta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp Scampi</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 lb shrimp 1&amp;frasl;3 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup cold butter cut into 1 Tbsp chunks 1&amp;frasl;2 cup white wine (pinot) 2 Tbsp garlic 2 tsp red pepper flakes 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp baking soda 2 Tbsp lemon juice 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chopped fresh parsley salt and pepper pasta french bread, sliced thin  Directions Thaw and peel your shrimp, then dry them well with paper towels. Put in a sealable bowl and toss with 1 tspn salt and 1&amp;frasl;4 tspn baking soda for 15 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Tomato Cream Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 pack sausage (chicken and apple sausage works well) 1 package mushrooms 1&amp;frasl;2 cup chicken stock (bullion water) 1 package noodles 1 big can tomatoes in sauce 0.5-1 cup heavy cream 1&amp;frasl;4 cup parmesan cheese olive oil butter 1 onion garlic  Spices:
 basil oregano parsley garlic powder rosemary thyme red pepper flakes cayenne powder  Directions Boil water for noodles.
Slice sausage and chop onion, saute in oil in very large pan until browned and happy looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat Sauce</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 pounds ground beef (I used ground round) 2 pounds sausage 3 tablespoons olive oil 2 large yellow onions, diced 2 green bell peppers, seeded and diced 3 cups fresh mushrooms, chopped 6 cloves garlic, minced 1 cup white wine or stock (your choice) Two 28-ounce cans crushed tomatoes One 24-ounce jar good store-bought marinara sauce One 6-ounce can tomato paste 2 tablespoons sugar 2 teaspoons kosher salt 2 teaspoon ground oregano 2 teaspoon ground thyme 2 teaspoon dried rosemary 3 teaspoon crushed red pepper, optional 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon cayenne, optional 5 bay leaves 1&amp;frasl;4 cup finely minced fresh parsley or 3 tablespoons parsley flakes (plus a little more for serving) 1 whole rind from 1 wedge Parmesan, optional 1&amp;frasl;2 cup grated Parmesan, optional (plus more for serving)  Makes a lot of sauce, you might want to halve it or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosemary Chicken and Mushroom Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 large boneless skinless chicken breasts 4 tbs butter, divided 1 tbs olive oil 10 oz package baby portabella mushrooms 1 clove garlic, minced 1.5 cup chicken stock 1 tsp crushed rosemary (or 1 large bruised sprig fresh) 1 tsp oregano 1 tsp thyme 1&amp;frasl;2 cup heavy cream (use less if you want to live past 50) pasta noodles of your choice  Seasoned Flour:
 1 cup flour 2 tsp salt 1 tsp pepper 2 tsp garlic powder  Instructions  Slice chicken in to thin strips roughly 2&amp;rdquo;x1&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac n Cheese</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tbsp butter 2 tbsp flout 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 2 cups milk 2 cups shredded white sharp cheddar cheese, divided 2 cups elbow macaroni, cooked and drained bread crumbs  Instructions  Preheat oven to 350 F
 Melt butter in saucepan on low heat, add flour and salt, mix well. Cook 2 minutes or until bubbly. Gradually add milk, stirring until well blended. Cook on medium heat until mixture boils and thickens, stirring constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Shrimp Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Shrimp and pasta  1 pound raw peeled and deveined shrimp 1&amp;frasl;4 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;8 cup parmesan cheese 4 garlic cloves, minced 2 teaspoons brown sugar 2 teaspoons soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon red pepper flakes 1 package pasta (linguine are my favorite) sliced green onion (garnish)  Cream sauce:  1 cup heavy cream 3 Tbsp butter 2 Tbsp parmesan cheese red pepper flakes cayenne pepper salt and pepper  Instructions In a bowl, whisk olive oil, parmesan, brown sugar, soy sauce, garlic and red pepper flakes together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesto</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups fresh basil leaves (lightly packed before cutting) 1&amp;frasl;2 cup fresh parsley (lightly packed before cutting) 3 cloves garlic 1&amp;frasl;2 cup grated Parmesan cheese 3&amp;frasl;4 cup olive oil 1&amp;frasl;4 cup pine nuts  Directions Chop everything up super fine, with a processor if you have one, or by hand if you&amp;rsquo;re up to a challenge. Combine all.
Serving suggestions: Serve with garlic-sauteed chicken over cavatappi pasta and a glass of mid-tier wine while watching Battlestar Galactica.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>