<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food for Thought </title>
    <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Nick Sharp</author>
    <rights>(C) 2020</rights>
    <updated>2020-03-26 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Focaccia</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/focaccia/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/focaccia/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For biga:
- 320g bread flour (all-purpose is fine too)
- 6g [&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp] instant yeast
- 215g water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For main dough:
- 500g all-purpose flour
- 12g [1 Tbsp] instant yeast
- 12g [2 tsp] salt
- 10g [1.5 tsp] honey
- 25g [2 Tbsp] olive oil (for dough, more as topping later)
- 300g [1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup] water
- Toppings of your choice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day before&lt;/strong&gt;: (15 min + 2 hrs)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the biga. Combine all ingredients and knead for 3-4 minutes. Dough should be slightly sitcky.  Ferment for ~2 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knead lightly to degas, and place in refridgerator overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes roughly triple what is needed for the focaccia. Store in the fridge for up to 3 days, or in a bag in the freezer for up ot 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bake day&lt;/strong&gt;: (t-minus 3-4 hours)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab 150g of biga, let it warm up if you have time (but if not, that&amp;rsquo;s fine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add flour, yeast, water, oil, and honey. Mix until combined, then work for 5-10 minutes. Should be soft and easy to work but not too sticky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the dough is cooperating, flop it on a flour counter. Roll out with a rolling pin, then fold back over itself and repeat several times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split the dough in half, or accept that you are making a single gigantic loaf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll the dough(s) in to a rectangle ~1cm thick and transfter to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Cover and let rise for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, prepare any toppings. I like to chop fresh/dried herbs and add the to some olive oil to make an herbed oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepare a brine with a 2:1 ratio of olive oil to water, and a healthy pinch of salt. Use herbed oil here if you have it. Use roughly &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of olive oil, but this is the moment to skimp make the bread healthier if you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 30 min has passed, uncover the bread, and push with your finger to make many dimples in the surface. Make the dimples as deep as possible without breaking through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drizzle the brine over the bread, making sure to get it in all the holes. It&amp;rsquo;ll look like too much, but its not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover the bread and let rise for another 1-2 hours, until roughly doubled in size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the over to 430F, and place any additional toppings on the bread. Bake for ~20 minutes, until golden brown on top and slightly crisped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove from oven and transfer immediately to cooling rack. Brush lightly with a little additional olive oil. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sesame Salmon and Green Beans</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sesame-salmon-and-green-beans/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sesame-salmon-and-green-beans/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; lb salmon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; lb green beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;splash of oil for cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;glaze&#34;&gt;glaze:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp rice wine (mirin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Tbsp toasted sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 clove garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inch fresh ginger, grated (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp sesame seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix all sauce ingredients in a small bowl, stir until cornstarch dissolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut salmon in to equal-sized steaks, you can leave the skin on if you like it. Place in bowl or bag and cover with half of the sauce. Marinade for ~15 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, rinse green beans and snap off ends. Snap big beans in half so pieces are ~1.5in long. Place in a medium saucepan with lukewarm water, cover and bring to a boil for about 3 min. Drain beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat a non-stick skillet and add splash of oil. Add salmon steaks to pan, but &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; add any additional marinade at this point. Cook for ~4 min / side, until almost cooked through. Remove and transfer to a separate plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add beans to the recently-vacated salmon pan and cover with remaining sauce. Cook, stirring frequently, just until sauce thickens and coats beans (~3 min).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plate rice, beans, and salmon. Salmon skin is edible if you want!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Japanese Milk Bread</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-milk-bread/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-milk-bread/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tangzhong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbs bread flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbs water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Tbs whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bread Dough:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;320g [2.5 cups] bread flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbs active dry yeast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbs unsalted butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg, room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egg wash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;splash of whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total time: 4-5 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take egg out of fridge to warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make tangzhong by combining all ingredients in a small saucepan and whisking rapidly over low heat. Once the mixture comes together to a thick paste, transfer to a bowl and allow to cool during next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm milk to ~90F (slightly above room temperature), then add yeast and mix. Allow to sit for ~10 min while proceeding with next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make dough by combining bread flour, salt, and sugar in a mixing bowl. Whisk together, then add milk/yeast, egg, and tangzong. Mix hand &amp;amp; knead (with dough hook if using mixer) until it comes together, scraping sides as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add in butter a little at a time, while mixing on medium-low. Once butter is all incorporated, knead (on medium) for ~5 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepare a bowl greased with butter. Turn dough on to counter, form in to boule with circular motions, then let rise in greased bowl covered with damp towel for 1-2 hrs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once dough has roughly doubled in size, prepare a greased baking pan (I use a 9in round pan). Turn dough out on to counter and punch down. Split dough in to 9 equal sized lumps, and roll each in to a happy round ball. Pack in pan, cover with damp towel, and let proof for another 1-2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 350F. Once rolls have expanded about 1.5x, brush with egg wash. Bake for 22-30 min, until golden brown on top. Brush with melted butter and sprinkle salt on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best served warm with apple butter!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sausage and Kale Pasta</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-and-kale-pasta/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-and-kale-pasta/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 package pasta, something small and squiggly (use half-package for less carbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 oz. chicken sausage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 oz. chopped kale (~1 bunch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 kalamata olives, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup grated Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp crushed red pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook pasta according to package; drop the pasta before before beginning next steps. &lt;strong&gt;Remember to reserve some pasta water.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice chicken sausage, and saute in a large pan with olive oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When sausage is browned, add garlic &amp;amp; butter and cook for one minute more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add chopped kale, olives, and ~1 cup pasta water to pan with sausage. Lower heat and cook, stirring occasionally, for 2-3 minutes until kale is wilted and has shrunk to an impossibly tiny size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove pan from heat, stir in the cooked &amp;amp; drained pasta, and allow to cool for a few minutes while stirring occasionally. I usually transfer to a separate large mixing bowl at this point (unless the pan you cooked in is truly gigantic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the pasta has cooled, add grated Parmesan, red pepper, and salt/pepper to taste. Stir to combine; ideally the Parmesan should coat the pasta but not melt. Optionally drizzle in a little additional EVOO for extra flavor. Serve immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Baked Brussel Sprouts</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/baked-brussel-sprouts/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brussel sprouts ~500g / ~1 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbs olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp red pepperflakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 500 degrees, with foil&amp;rsquo;d baking sheet inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinse sprouts, cut each in half. Toss with oil and spices in large bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put sprouts on hot baking sheet, flip them fast so cut side is down and return to oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake for ~20 min, untill browned and crispy on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Basic Bread</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/basic-bread/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/basic-bread/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400g [3 cups] bread flour (or AP flour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1g [&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp] instant yeast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8g [1 tsp] salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;300g [1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup] water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day before&lt;/strong&gt;: (~15 min)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine flour, yeast, and salt in large bowl. Add water and mix until combined, then 30sec more. Dough should be wet and sticky, and not hold shape at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover bowl with towel or wrap, and let sit at room temperature for 12-24 hours. Surface should be bubbly after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bake day&lt;/strong&gt;: (t-minus 4 hours)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flour work surface and hands. Prepare a cotton towel sitting on the counter, dusted with flour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dump the dough on to your surface in an ugly blob; it won&amp;rsquo;t want to leave the bowl so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to evict it with a rubber spatula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab the top of the dough blob, stretch it slightly, and fold it over the center; repeat on other three sides. You want to create some tension in the sides of the dough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow pick up the dough and place it on the towel you prepared, so the top seam side you were just folding is now facing down. Ideally, you want to preserve the tension of the dough, but don&amp;rsquo;t mess with it once you&amp;rsquo;ve set it down. It will be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dust the top of the dough with flour, cover with the sides of the towel, and let it rise for ~2 hours. It&amp;rsquo;s done when poking leaves a persistent impression. With about 30 min to go, preheat the oven to 450F and place a heavy pot with lid inside (dutch oven / cast iron / pyrex / etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the dough has risen, pull the hot pot out of the oven. Awkwardly flop the dough out of the towel and in to the pan, so the seam side which was facing down is now facing up. It&amp;rsquo;s fine if the dough isn&amp;rsquo;t nicely centered. (Nick has burnt himself ≥ 3 times doing this. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like Nick.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place lid on pot and return to oven. Use a spray bottle (or really anything) to thoroughly spray the inside of the oven with water and make some steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake for 30 minutes, then remove the lid from the pot and bake 10-30 minutes more, until the bread is a medium brown color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove from oven and immediately transfer to wire rack. Let cool completely before slicing and eating, at least 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Braised Pork Belly</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ramen-eggs&#34;&gt;Ramen Eggs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup Japanese soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 piece kombu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup mirin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup cooking sake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup bonito flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 cloves garlic crushed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;braised-beef&#34;&gt;Braised beef&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb pork belly or shoulder, cut to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; in cubes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp shaoxing wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp dark soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup fried shallots/onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp garlic, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 star anise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dried shiitake mushrooms, soaked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 stick cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp rock sugar or brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup hot water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10-15 dried chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp sichuan bean paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tsp sambal olek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp chili crisp oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ramen-egg&#34;&gt;Ramen Egg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil a large pot of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make tare by combining all ingredients (except egg) in saucepan, simmer for 15 min. Strain with fine sieve and let cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place in warm water for 1 minute (if eggs are room-temperature already, skip this step and boil for 1 minute less below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower eggs in water, boil for 7 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; min. Prepare bowl of ice water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move eggs to ice water for a few minutes to cool. Peel under running water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place eggs in a ziploc bag with ~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of the tare, enough to soak but no need to totally submerge. Refrigerate for 8-24 hours, turning occasionally. Remove eggs from tare and refrigerate. Remaining tare can be re-used a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use eggs within 3 days. Leftover tare sauce seems to keep for a very long time. Before using eggs, let them come to room temperature if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;braised-beef-1&#34;&gt;Braised Beef&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set instant pot to sauté (high/more temp). Add vegetable oil to bottom. Once oil is hot, add pork and keep it moving to avoid sticking. The pork will give off some water, cook until that water is mostly evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix all other ingredients (except cornstarch) in separate bowl. Once water has cooked off pork, add to instant pot and stir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set instant pot to manual, high pressure, 25 minutes. Once finished, wait for a natural pressure release (quick release is fine if you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry). Skim off oil from mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set instant pot to sauté on high again, and cook until pork has darkened a little and some (but not all) of the liquid has evaporated. If in doubt, leave more liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix 1 part cornstarch to 2 parts water (by volume), and stir in to mixture until a thick saucy consistency is reached. Usually around 3 Tbsp of the mixture will do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serving suggestion: ladle pork over rice, top with ramen egg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Portobello Caps</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/portobello-caps/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/portobello-caps/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 large portobello caps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; cup canola (or other high heat) oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbs balsamic vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dijon mustard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black pepper
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean mushrooms, remove stems, scrape out gills. Slice if desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine all other ingredients to make marinade. Cover mushrooms and let sit for ~1hr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grill for ~10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things to try / optional additions:
- 3 Tbs chopped onion
- rosemary
- cayenne&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sweet Potato Fries</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-potato-fries/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2lbs sweet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbs olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp paprika&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 425 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peel potatoes if the skin bothers you. Slice potatoes in to strips &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; inch wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix spices with oil, toss with potatoes in large bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spread fries on baking sheet; be sure to leave lots of space between and use two sheets if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake ~30 minutes, flipping halfway through. If not crisping, broil for ~3 minutes at the end (but be careful, they burn fast while broiling).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 potato each is decent serving&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider adding: cayenne, old bay&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possibly use oil spritzer to cut down on oil?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Japanese Curry</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2 lb chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 lb yukon gold potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups chicken stock (bullion works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 package curry cubes (~200g, I use &amp;ldquo;Golden Curry&amp;rdquo; brand)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp tomato paste (can use ketchup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;optional-additions&#34;&gt;Optional additions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 apple, grated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; bar chocolate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pinch of cheddar cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon honey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peel and chop potatoes in to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inch cubes, put in a bowl with water to de-starch while doing next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chop chicken and onion, saute with garlic to get some browning (don&amp;rsquo;t need to actually cook it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peel and chop carrot in to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inch cubes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put all ingredients except tomato paste and soy sauce in instant pot. Set to meat/stew (high pressure) for 15 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After instant pot finishes, let pressure release naturally. Then, stir in tomato paste and soy sauce. Serve over rice!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Beef Stew</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb beef stew meat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 oz mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 lb potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14 oz bag frozen pearl onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups beef broth (bullion works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If stew beef is coarsely cut, further cut in to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-in cubes. Toss with flour, salt, and pepper to coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean and chop all vegetables. Use &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-in chunks of potatoes, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-in chuncks of carrots and mushrooms. Pearl onions can be used directly from frozen bag without thawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melt butter in a large skillet, then add beef and saute. Keep the temperature high and try not to touch it except once to flip. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to cook the beef through, but we do want a good browning on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove beef from pot, then add beef broth to deglaze. Add all spices and sauce to skillet and this point and mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add all ingredients to pressure cooker (or instant pot). Cook on high for 35 minutes (for instant pot, use meat/stew setting). After 35 minutes, let pressure naturally dissipate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open steam valve and serve! Bread is a must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially adapted from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.budgetbytes.com/2017/01/instant-pot-beef-stew/&#34;&gt;https://www.budgetbytes.com/2017/01/instant-pot-beef-stew/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Pork Bowl Stir Fry with Peanut Sauce</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pork-bowl-stir-fry-with-peanut-sauce/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pork-bowl-stir-fry-with-peanut-sauce/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spicy-peanut-sauce&#34;&gt;Spicy Peanut Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; cup natural-style peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp sriracha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp grated fresh ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp hot water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pork-mixture&#34;&gt;Pork Mixture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb ground pork, chicken or turkey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 oz button mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large carrot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 red bell pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp grated fresh ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp toasted sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Tbsp neutral cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bowl&#34;&gt;Bowl&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cups cooked rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup peanuts, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 green onions, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sauce by combining all ingredients in small bowl. Add water slowly until thin enough to drizzle, but no more. Set aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saute garlic, ginger, and pork in a skillet until pork is cooked through and crumbly, about five minutes. While cooking, clean and chop mushrooms in to small pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once pork is cooked, add mushrooms to the skillet and continue cooking until they have released their moisture (about 5 min). Meanwhile, shred carrot and dice bell pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once mushrooms are cooked through, add carrots, bell pepper, hoisin sauce, soy sauce, and sesame oil to the skillet. Stir over heat until combined and heated through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially adapted from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.budgetbytes.com/2016/04/hoisin-stir-fry-bowls-spicy-peanut-sauce/&#34;&gt;https://www.budgetbytes.com/2016/04/hoisin-stir-fry-bowls-spicy-peanut-sauce/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Shredded Chicken</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp canola, vegetable or avocado oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 lbs boneless skinless chicken, cubed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; yellow onion, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp coriander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp kosher sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 2 oranges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 2 limes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; jalapeño, minced (or a whole pepper if you prefer slightly spicier)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; c. fresh cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saute chicken with a small amount of oil and garlic. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to cook through, just brown the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add chicken and all remaining ingrdients to pressure cooker. Cook on high (instant pot &amp;ldquo;poultry&amp;rdquo; setting) for 12 minutes. Immediately release pressure using an oven mitt and wait for steam to release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saute the mixture until almost all remaining liquid is gone (can use instant pot &amp;ldquo;saute&amp;rdquo; setting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shred using utensils or bowl mixer. Use to make quesadillas, tacos, or any other delicious thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially adapted from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifemadesimplebakes.com/2017/07/instant-pot-shredded-chicken-tacos/&#34;&gt;http://lifemadesimplebakes.com/2017/07/instant-pot-shredded-chicken-tacos/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Beef Bulgogi</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-bulgogi/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-bulgogi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 lb beef (flank, sirloin, or strip cuts usually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large zucchini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;peanut oil (or similar, for cooking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion (chopped long and thin, divided)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 stalks green onion (chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; asian pear (peeled and chunked)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp sesame seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp sriracha sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp Korean red pepper powder (&amp;ldquo;gochugaru&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slice beef in to long thin strips. These should basically be as thin as you can get them by hand. It may help to put the meat in the freezer for a short time (30-60 minutes) right beforehand, as it firms up the beef and makes it easier to slice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make the marinade from all ingredients except beef, zucchini, and peanut oil. Reserve half of the chopped onion, and blend everything else together, then add in the remaining onion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Place the beef and marinade in a large container, mix thoroughly then marinade in the refrigerator for 2-24 hours, agitating occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When ready to prepare, remove the meat from the fridge and allow it to come to room temperature approximately an hour ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Place some peanut oil in a hot wok, and cook the strips of beef. Remove the beef from the marinade with tongs to avoid getting too much liquid in the pan and steaming the meat rather than searing it. Do several batches as necessary to avoid crowding the pan. The beef should cook quite quickly ~3-5 minutes per batch. Mix the zucchini in to each batch about half way through, and at the very end of the batch add in some of the sauce to heat and combine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serve over rice and be happy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Chicken:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup whole milk yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp garam masala (okay to substitute curry powder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp ground coriander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 2-inch chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Sauce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon finely chopped fresh ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.25 tsp garam masala (okay to substitute curry powder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.25 tsp ground coriander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.75 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 (14-oz) can crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup chopped fresh cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bowl large enough to hold the chicken, whisk together the yogurt, salt and spices. Add the chicken and mix until it is evenly coated. Cover and marinate in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour or overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the broiler and set an oven rack in the top position. Line a baking sheet with aluminum foil and set a wire rack on top; spray the rack with nonstick cooking spray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the chicken on the prepared rack, spooning any marinade left in the bowl over the chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broil for 7 to 8 minutes, until browned on top. (The chicken does not need to be flipped over.) While the chicken cooks, start the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the sauce: Melt the butter over medium heat in a large pan. Add the onions and ginger and cook, stirring frequently, until softened, 5 to 7 minutes. Do not brown; reduce the heat if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the spices and cook 2 minutes more. Add the tomatoes, heavy cream, salt, sugar, pepper and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup water. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer, uncovered, until thickened, about 15 minutes. Taste and adjust seasoning if necessary (I usually add a bit more salt and sugar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the broiled chicken to the sauce and simmer until the chicken is warmed through and fully cooked, a few minutes. Sprinkle the cilantro over the chicken and serve with buttered Indian basmati rice and/or naan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;original-from&#34;&gt;Original from:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onceuponachef.com/recipes/chicken-tikka-masala.html&#34;&gt;http://www.onceuponachef.com/recipes/chicken-tikka-masala.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Shrimp Scampi</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shrimp-scampi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb shrimp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup cold butter cut into 1 Tbsp chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup white wine (pinot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup chopped fresh parsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;french bread, sliced thin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thaw and peel your shrimp, then dry them well with paper towels. Put in a sealable bowl and toss with 1 tspn salt and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tspn baking soda for 15 mins. This makes them plump but sear well when cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prep ingredients. Cut the butter up but keep in fridge until needed so it stays cold. Chop the parsley and put in a ramekin. Boil water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut your French bread into thin slices and preheat the oven to 350.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a cast iron, start with a thin layer of olive oil and once hitting light smoke, drop in shrimp. Cook until color is good and then remove to aluminum foil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start cooking pasta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove cast iron from the heat, and add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup olive oil to cast iron, along with the garlic and red pepper flakes. It should be sizzling good but not burning.
Once garlic is fragrant but not overcooked, add in the wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stir it all together, and then let it simmer well until reduced by about half and the raw alcohol smell is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover bread with a light layer of olive oil and put in oven to toast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the cold butter, 1 Tbsp at a time, and CONSTANTLY WHISK. This is what makes the sauce smooth and not watery. After all butter has been introduced, add lemon just and reduce to low heat. The bread will be done at some point around here, don&amp;rsquo;t burn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, add the shrimp back and toss and coat and put back on heat until just starting to sizzle and warmed again. Add most of the parsley and stir together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, scoot your shrimp over to one half of the cast iron, and put your pasta in the other half. Mix it with the butter/oil mix in the cast iron so it gets a good coat, then put neatly back on its half of the cast iron.
Salt and pepper the pasta, and then sprinkle the last bit of parsley over all of it as a topping. Place the toasted bread around the outer ring of cast iron on top the pasta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artfully position the bread around the cast iron pan and take a picture, it will do well on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Oatmeal Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/oatmeal-chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/oatmeal-chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup packed light brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup white sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 cups quick-cooking oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup chopped walnuts/pecans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup semisweet chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup white chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F (165 degrees C).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large bowl, cream together the butter, brown sugar, and white sugar until smooth. Beat in eggs one at a time, then stir in vanilla. Combine the flour, baking soda, and salt; stir into the creamed mixture until just blended. Mix in the quick oats, walnuts, and chocolate chips. Drop by heaping spoonfuls onto ungreased baking sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake for 12 minutes in the preheated oven. Allow cookies to cool on baking sheet for 5 minutes before transferring to a wire rack to cool completely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sausage Tomato Cream Pasta</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sausage-tomato-cream-pasta/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pack sausage (chicken and apple sausage works well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 package mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup chicken stock (bullion water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 package noodles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 big can tomatoes in sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5-1 cup heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup parmesan cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cayenne powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil water for noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice sausage and chop onion, saute in oil in very large pan until browned and happy looking. Add garlic and some of the other spices at some point. It may work well to cook sausage in a separate, nonstick pan first for ~5 min, then add to main pan with onions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice mushrooms, cook in oil and butter. Add some garlic and spices at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deglaze sausage pan with chicken stock. Add can of tomatoes, breaking up large chunks. Add remainder of spices. Cook down until it reduces to be thick instead of liquidy (~20 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start cooking noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t like crunchy bits, remove sausage from pan and blend rest of sauce before returning to pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add heavy cream, mushrooms, cheese, and remainder of spices to sausage pot. Cook until cream reduces a bit (~5 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add noodles to main pot, stir to combine and serve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Meat Sauce</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/meat-sauce/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 pounds ground beef (I used ground round)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pounds sausage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 large yellow onions, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 green bell peppers, seeded and diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups fresh mushrooms, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup white wine or stock (your choice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two 28-ounce cans crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One 24-ounce jar good store-bought marinara sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One 6-ounce can tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon ground oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon ground thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon dried rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 teaspoon crushed red pepper, optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon cayenne, optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup finely minced fresh parsley or 3 tablespoons parsley flakes (plus a little more for serving)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 whole rind from 1 wedge Parmesan, optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup grated Parmesan, optional (plus more for serving)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of sauce, you might want to halve it or more. Freezes well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large pot over medium-high heat, brown the ground beef and sausage until totally browned. Remove the meat from the pot with a slotted spoon and put it into a bowl. Set aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discard any grease in the pot, but do not clean the pot. Drizzle in the olive oil. When it is heated, throw in the onions and bell peppers. Stir it around for 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; minutes, and then add the garlic. Stir and cook for an additional minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pour in the wine and allow it to bubble up and reduce for about 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; minutes. Add the crushed tomatoes, marinara sauce and tomato paste. Stir to combine, and then add the sugar, salt, oregano, thyme, red pepper and cayenne (if using) and bay leaves. Stir, and then add the cooked ground beef and sausage and stir to combine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saute mushrooms in oil (and butter?) until they look yummy, add to pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the lid on the pot and allow to simmer for 1 hour, stirring occasionally. Add a little water or some low-sodium broth if it needs more liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour, add the minced parsley and the Parmesan rind if using (or grated Parmesan if you prefer&amp;ndash;or both!). Stir to combine, and then put the lid back on and allow it to simmer for another 30 minutes or so. Discard the bay leaves before serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve a big bowl of oiled noodles and the meat sauce so guests can serve themselves. Top each serving with minced parsley and grated Parmesan (or Parmesan shavings) and serve with a big piece of garlic-cheese bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/ree-drummond/meat-sauce&#34;&gt;http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/ree-drummond/meat-sauce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things to try:
- Yellow mustard
- Worcestire sauce
- (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/AskCulinary/comments/6igqit/my_familys_recipes_say_to_add_yellow_mustard_to/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/AskCulinary/comments/6igqit/my_familys_recipes_say_to_add_yellow_mustard_to/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Barley Soup</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/barley-soup/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/barley-soup/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 qts water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 ham hocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup split peas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup barley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup chopped onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup chopped celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 potatoes, cubed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook ham hocks in water for 2 hours (note: may be too long for smallish ham hocks, maybe try less)
Add barley, split peas, celery and onion, simmer 2.5 - 3 hours.
Remove ham from hocks, trim off fat.  Return meat to pot.
Add cubed potatoes and simmer an additional hour or two.
Salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should be a very thick soup.  I also usually make three times the recipe as it freezes quite well (although sometimes I need to add a little water when I heat it up)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe dates back at least to Nick’s great-grandmother (Lanny Stell) who was born in Austria in 1908.  She came to America when she was 12.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Eggplant Parmesan</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/eggplant-parmesean/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/eggplant-parmesean/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 c chopped onion (or oil works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 clove garlic, mashed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 lb ground chuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cans tomato sauce (8 oz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 tsp dried oregano leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp dried basil leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; tsp anise seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 large eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 eggs, slightly beaten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; c dried bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; c grated Parmesan cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 c vegetable or olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 c mozzarella cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a skillet melt butter/oil. Sauté onions, garlic and meat for about 5 minutes. Add tomato sauce, oregano, basil and anise. Mix well and set aside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 350 F. Lightly grease 12x8x2 baking dish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash eggplant, slice crosswise &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo; thick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a pie plate, combine eggs and 1 tablespoon water, mix well. In another pie plate combine bread crumbs with &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup Parmesan cheese, mix well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dip eggplant slices into egg mixture, coating well. Then dip into crumb mixture, coating evenly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saute eggplant slices in a little hot oil or until golden brown and crisp on both sides. Add more oil if needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place a single layer of eggplant into bottom of prepared baking dish. Sprinkle with some of the remaining Parmesan cheese, top with a few slices of mozzarella cheese, cover with tomato sauce. Repeat layering until all ingredients used, making sure to cover the top completely with mozzarella cheese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake uncovered for 20 minutes or until cheese is melted and bubbles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select eggplants that are relatively heavy for their size, with skins that are smooth, taut, and shiny. Tan patches, scars, or bruises on the skin are signs of decay underneath. When you press an eggplant with your thumb, it should feel firm and bounce back. The fuzzy caps and stems should be green and free of decay and mold. Eggplants are perishable,  buy them no more than a day or two in advance and store them in a plastic bag in a cool place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ready to use, slice the eggplants, set on a paper towel and then lightly salt the rounds and leave on about  20  minutes before wiping off the salt. This will remove some of the water in the eggplants, and they will absorb less oil during cooking. It also takes away the bitterness of the eggplant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I made it  I used 3 small eggplants (about .8 lb each).  I used  1.3 lbs of grd beef and I used a 13 x9x2 cake pan and put in 3 layers.  The fresh mozzarella was great on the top and probably world be good throughout.  I used plain bread crumbs but next time  I make it I think I would like to try mixing Italain and panko. I cooked it longer closer to  30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think if you cut the recipe in half you could put it in a 8x8 pan or a deep dish pie plate.  If you have extra eggplant bread it and fry it you can freeze it like that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Cornbread</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/cornbread/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 boxes Jiffy cornbread muffin mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can creamed corn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbs Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbs butter (to grease skillet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Find a cast iron skillet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine all ingredients in bowl. Mix and allow to sit for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the skillet in the oven for a few minutes to allow it to warm up. Take out the skillet and coat the inside with butter (or fat). Then pour in the batter (it should sizzle!) and return the skillet to the oven. Bake for 25-35 minutes, until the top of the cornbread is brown and cracking. Remember to clean the skillet as soon as possible to prevent rusting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Rice Bowl with Chinese sausage</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rice-bowl-with-chinese-sausage/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rice-bowl-with-chinese-sausage/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups (rice cooker cups) white rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2 cups chicken stock (amount depends on rice cooker)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; package Chinese sausage (maybe &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb ish?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups frozen mixed veggies (peas/corn/carrots/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup crushed pineapple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.5 Tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tbs sriracha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other spices as desired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinse and cut broccoli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin cooking rice the usual way (rinse it, you fool!), except use chicken stock instead of water. Add broccoli on top immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice chinese sausage, add it to a bowl to marinade with all off the sauces/spices combined&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam frozen veggies. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about fully cooking them, but you want them to be warm. Add veggies to marinading bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When 10 min are left on rice cooker, add sausage/veggie/sauce mixture and stir. Set broccoli above to steam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eat, be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock instead of water with rice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might need to cook broccoli separate to get it to be done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other spices? fish sauce?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Rosemary Chicken and Mushroom Pasta</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/rosemary-chicken-and-mushrooms-with-cream-sauce/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 large boneless skinless chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 tbs butter, divided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbs olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 oz package baby portabella mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 clove garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 cup chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp crushed rosemary (or 1 large bruised sprig fresh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup heavy cream (use less if you want to live past 50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pasta noodles of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seasoned Flour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slice chicken in to thin strips roughly 2&amp;rdquo;x1&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mix the seasoned flour ingredients together in a gallon plastic bag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add chicken to bag and shake vigorously to coat. Cook through in a skillet with half of butter. While these are cooking, cook the mushrooms separately in the next two steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean and cut mushrooms in to large slices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heat remaining 2 tbs of butter and the 1 tbs of olive oil in a large skillet over medium high heat. Add mushrooms, sauteing until most liquid has evaporated. Add the garlic with roughly 5 minutes remaining.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the chicken is done cooking, add the 1 cup of stock and the rosemary to deglaze the pan. Add mushrooms to this pan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cover, reduce heat and cook for 20 minutes until liquid has reduced and thickened significantly. Also start boiling water for noodles at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If using fresh rosemary, pick out the sprigs at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the cream and heat through over medium-low heat until the sauce is reduced by 25%. This should only take about 5 minutes after it begins to bubble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spoon mixture over pasta and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Black Bean Chicken Quesadillas</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/black-bean-chicken-quesadillas/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/black-bean-chicken-quesadillas/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb, chicken tenderloin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 (15 oz.) can black beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup frozen corn kernels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; small red onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 clove garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; bunch fresh cilantro, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 (~2 Tbs) batch taco seasoning (try chili powder and cayenne)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 taco sized tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fresh squeezed lime (to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oil to cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook chicken with some garlic and oil. Chop up everything else.
Mix everything together in a giant bowl. Make quesadillas in a greased nonstick pan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>French Toast</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/french-toast/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/french-toast/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 slices challah, brioche, or white bread&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup maple syrup, warmed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a small bowl, combine, cinnamon, nutmeg, and sugar and set aside briefly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 10-inch or 12-inch skillet, melt butter over medium heat. Whisk together cinnamon mixture, eggs, milk, and vanilla and pour into a shallow container such as a pie plate. Dip bread in egg mixture. Fry slices until golden brown, then flip to cook the other side. Serve with syrup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Texas Trash</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/texas-trash/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 small can chopped black olives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 small can green chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 large tomatoes (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 green onions (chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp Olive Oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp Garlic salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix and chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve with tortilla chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been adding some black pepper and using a combination of
roma and regular tomatoes.  You need to have juice so you can&amp;rsquo;t use all
romas - I also find better to use a little more tomatoes rather than less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you find it is too juicy when you take it out of the fridge, simply
spoon off some liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things to try:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add fresh diced jalapenos?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Twice Baked Potatoes</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/twice-baked-potatoes/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 sticks of butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup Sour Cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;milk (if necessary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2 cups Cheddar/Jack Cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Bacon Bits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 green onions (chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp Lawry’s Seasoned Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp garlic salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake potatoes at 400 for 1:15 or until cooked through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halve the potatoes and scoop out the insides, try to preserve the skins. Mix the potato innards with all of the other ingredients (using only half of the cheese).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoop the mix back in to the skins and bake at 350 for 15-20 min. Top with remaining cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Spiced Apple Cider</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/apple-cider/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/apple-cider/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gal apple cider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fresh orange, sliced (with peel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cinnamon sticks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 tsp whole cloves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of a nutmeg, ground/smashed (or &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp nutmeg powder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients-1&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine all ingredients and heat. The spices will get stronger over the next few hours,
I suggest waiting at least 2 hours to drink. Strain it out to pour in to cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s hot but not too hot (I use roughly 175F). If there is A LOT of steam coming off of the pot then the liquid is evaporating too fast and it will quickly get syrupy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe originally from Aunt Nan!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Stir Fry with Chicken and Broccoli</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-and-spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups broccoli florets (frozen steam broccoli works, follow bag directions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2 cups stir fry veggie mix -&amp;gt; sugar peas, mushrooms, peppers? (if you can find a frozen one just chuck it in frozen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves - cut into 1 inch strips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup sliced green onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon chile paste (sriracha works!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon low sodium soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon crushed red pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dash of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; cup chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place broccoli in a steamer over 1 inch of boiling water, and cover. Cook until tender but still firm, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat the oil in a skillet over medium heat, and saute the chicken, green onions, and garlic until the chicken is no longer pink and juices run clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir the hoisin sauce, chile paste, and soy sauce into the skillet. Season with ginger, red pepper, salt, and black pepper. Stir in the chicken stock and simmer about 2 minutes. Mix in the steamed broccoli until coated with the sauce mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mac n Cheese</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/arndorfer-mac-n-cheese/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbsp flout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups shredded white sharp cheddar cheese, divided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups elbow macaroni, cooked and drained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 350 F&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Melt butter in saucepan on low heat, add flour and salt, mix well. Cook 2 minutes or until bubbly. Gradually add milk, stirring until well blended. Cook on medium heat until mixture boils and thickens, stirring constantly. Reduce heat to low, simmer for 3-5 minutes or until thickened. Add 1-&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cups of cheese, cook until melted, stirring constantly. Add macaroni; mix lightly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spoon in to 1-&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; quart casserole, sprinkle with remaining &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cheese.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sprinkle top with bread crumbs, dot with butter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bake 20 min or until heated through&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Chili</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chili/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chili/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 lbs ground beef&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lbs chorizo sausage (not in casing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large yellow onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 15oz can black beans (strain out ~half the juice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 15oz can kidney beans (strain out ~half the juice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 14oz can diced tomatoes  (dump entire can)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 14oz can stewed tomatoes (dump entire can)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 jalapenos, seeded and diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; bottle of beer (IPA works great)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 shots whiskey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1+ teaspoons cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I often make a double batch of this recipe, which ends up being about 12 bowls of chili.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put a large pot over medium heat with all of the canned ingredients, everything gets added in here as it is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown the meat with some of the chili powder. Leave some of the fat in the pan, and use it to saute onions until they are starting to caramelize, adding the garlic with about 5 minutes to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deglaze the pan with the whiskey and beer, reduce slightly, and add the mixture to the pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the remaining spices (but not the jalapenos) to the pot. I normally add about 1 tsp of cayenne now, then add more in later to taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simmer for about 2 hours. Keep it just barely boiling and stir every ~20 minutes to ensure nothing sticks to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add jalapenos. Simmer for at least another hour. It&amp;rsquo;s chili &amp;ndash; serve it whenever you damn please.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Spicy Shrimp Pasta</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/spicy-parmesan-shrimp-skillet/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shrimp-and-pasta&#34;&gt;Shrimp and pasta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pound raw peeled and deveined shrimp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; cup parmesan cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 package pasta (linguine are my favorite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sliced green onion (garnish)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cream-sauce&#34;&gt;Cream sauce:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp parmesan cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bowl, whisk olive oil, parmesan, brown sugar, soy sauce, garlic and red pepper flakes together. Add shrimp to a large ziplock bag, pour marinade over top, then seal bag and shake to coat. Place in the fridge to marinate for at least 30 minutes, up to overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ready to eat, bring water to boil in a large pot and cook pasta according to directions. While pasta is cooking, heat a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add shrimp and marinade (just dump the entire contents of the bag into the skillet), then cook shrimp until pink – about 3-4 minutes per side. If you cook for too long, the brown sugar from the marinade will start to blacken and smoke, this is bad! Once the shrimp are done, remove them and make the cream sauce in the pot, combining all ingredients and cooking over low heat until the sauce has reduced by a third. Serve shrimp over pasta and top with cream sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Chicken Couscous</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-and-couscous/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/chicken-and-couscous/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups celery, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cups Israeli (Pearl) Couscous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb chicken, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large skillet, heat olive oil over medium high heat. Add onion, carrots, and celery, season with salt and pepper, and saute for 5-10 minutes until softened and caramelized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add garlic and stir to combine until fragrant, about 30 seconds. Add couscous and broth, stir to combine, then cover, reduce heat to low, and simmer for 8-10 minutes until broth is absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add chicken and stir until heated through.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sweet Tea</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-tea/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/sweet-tea/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Makes 1 Gallon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.25 cups sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 gallon filtered water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 tea bags (I use plain Lipton bags)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add baking soda to 4 cups of water, boil&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove from heat, add tea bags to boiled water and steep for 15 min, remove without squeezing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stir in sugar until dissolved&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add remaining water&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Peppermint Bark</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/peppermint-bark/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/peppermint-bark/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 ounces dark chocolate (morsels work great)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 ounces white chocolate (morsels work great)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vegetable oil (flavorless oil)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 candy cane&amp;rsquo;s worth of ground up candy canes (Peppermints probably also work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line a cookie sheet with aluminum foil. This recipe makes about the right amount for about half of a standard baking sheet. Consider a double recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melt dark chocolate with 1 tsp vegetable oil. I suggest the microwave (see note at bottom) unless you have a double boiler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spread dark chocolate in the cookie sheet. Place in refrigerator until set, about 30 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melt white chocolate with 1 tsp vegetable oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spread white chocolate in the cookie sheet on top of dark. Quickly sprinkle crushed candy cane on top, pressing lightly to get it to stick. Place in refrigerator until set, about 30 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To melt 10 oz chocolate for this recipe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place in uncovered microwavable bowl (with oil)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave for 1 min on 70% power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir a lot. Should still have some morsel-ness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave for 15 sec on 70% power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir a bunch more. Should be almost a liquid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave for 15 sec on 70% power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir. Should be fully liquid (pourable) now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Egg Salad</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/egg-salad/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons mayonnaise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &amp;amp; &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tablespoons prepared Dijon-style mustard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon dried dill weed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon paprika&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; red onion, minced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place eggs in a saucepan and cover with cold water. Bring water to a boil; cover, remove from heat, and let eggs stand in hot water for 10 to 12 minutes. Remove from hot water, cool, peel and chop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large bowl, combine the egg, mayonnaise, mustard, dill, paprika, onion and salt and pepper. Mash well with a fork or wooden spoon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Pesto</title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/pesto/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups fresh basil leaves (lightly packed before cutting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup fresh parsley (lightly packed before cutting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup grated Parmesan cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup pine nuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chop everything up super fine, with a processor if you have one, or by hand if you&amp;rsquo;re up to a challenge. Combine all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;serving-suggestions&#34;&gt;Serving suggestions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve with garlic-sauteed chicken over cavatappi pasta and a glass
of mid-tier wine while watching Battlestar Galactica.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title></title>
          <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/drinks/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Nick Sharp</author>
          <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/drinks/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;em&gt;JAGER BOMB&lt;/em&gt; boil 1 cup red bull (in place of water), add black cherry or orange jello, 1 cups jager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;em&gt;MARGARITA&lt;/em&gt; boil 1 cup water, add 3 oz pkg lime jello, 4 oz tequila, 4 oz sweet &amp;amp; sour margarita mix. sprinkle with salt just before firm.
(substitue watermelon jello for lime for a melon margarita)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 *RUM &amp;amp; COKE boil 1 cups coke, mix in dark cherry jello add 1 cups light rum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;em&gt;MIMOSAS&lt;/em&gt; this one varies from the normal method Since champagne isn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as liquor, cut the water out of this one. boil one cup champagne, mix orange jello 2 min, add one more cup champagne and a splash of OJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 &lt;em&gt;SILK&lt;/em&gt; Boil one cup champagne, mix in jello for 2 minutes, add one cup champagne and splash of lychee juice from the can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 &lt;em&gt;ORANGE TIC TAC&lt;/em&gt; Boil two cups red bull, mix jello two minutes, add two cups mandarin orange vodka&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 &lt;em&gt;LEMON DROP&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add lemon jello, citrus vodka, top with sugar sprinkles just before its fully set up)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 &lt;em&gt;GRAPE CRUSH&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cups water, add grape jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup plain vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup chambord)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 &lt;em&gt;HAWAIIAN&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add pineapple or blueberry jello, 1 cup coconut rum)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 &lt;em&gt;GIN &amp;amp; TONIC&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup tonic water, add lime jello, 1 cup gin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 &lt;em&gt;LEMON LIME&lt;/em&gt; (boil 2 cups sprite, add lemon and lime jellos, 2 cups citrus vodka)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 &lt;em&gt;BLUEBERRY&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add blueberry jello, 1 cup blueberry vodka)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 &lt;em&gt;FRUIT PUNCH&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cups water, add mixed fruit jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup blueberry vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup raspberry vodka)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 &lt;em&gt;WATERMELON&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add watermelon jello,1 cup watermelon vodka)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 &lt;em&gt;BEER&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cups water, add strawberry jello, add 1 cup any malt liquor)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 &lt;em&gt;CARIBBEAN&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add strawberry-banana jello, Cruzan banana rum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17 &lt;em&gt;CHERRY COLA&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup coke, add cherry jello, 1 cup cold cola, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup amaretto, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup spiced rum)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18 &lt;em&gt;DREAMSICLE&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup water &amp;amp; &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup OJ, add orange jello, 1 cup vanilla vodka &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup raspberry or berry vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup KeKe Beach Key Lime Cream Liqueur)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 &lt;em&gt;LIME IN THE COCONUT&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add watermelon jello, 1 cup Malibu Coconut Rum)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 &lt;em&gt;RED HOTS&lt;/em&gt; (boil 2 cups water, add jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup cold water, 2 cups Cinnamon Schnapps)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21 &lt;strong&gt;SEX ON THE BEACH&lt;/strong&gt; boil 1 cup cranberry juice, add 3 oz pkg orange jello, 3 oz peach schnapps, 5 oz vodka&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SOUR APPLE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (in microwavable container, mix 1 small box sour apple jello, 1 pkg knox gelatin and 1 tbs sugar. Stir in 1 cup Mt. Dew and mix well. Microwave on high for 1 min. Stir until powder is dissolved. Mix 2 cups vodka &amp;amp; &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup Captain Morgan Coconut Rum. mix well and let sit 1 min. pour into cups and refrigerate.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23 &lt;em&gt;SQUIRM&lt;/em&gt; (boil 2 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup water, add 3 small pkgs any flavor jello, 2 cups vodka, &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ice cold water. add 1 gummy worm to each shot before firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24 &lt;em&gt;CARIBOU LOU&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup boiling water &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup pineapple juice boiled, add pineapple jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Malibu Rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Triplesec)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25 &lt;em&gt;JOLLY RANCHER&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add melon jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup apple pucker)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26 &lt;em&gt;PURPLE PEOPLE EATER&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add grape jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup watermelon pucker)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27 &lt;em&gt;BAHAMA MAMA&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add watermelon jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Malibu rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup peach schnapps)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28 &lt;em&gt;COSMOPOLITAN&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water with a splash of lime juice, add cranberry jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup triple sec)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29 &lt;em&gt;CHERRY BOMB&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup redbull, add cherry jello, 1 cup vodka and drop in one maraschino cherry, step up before firmed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 &lt;em&gt;BLUE FIRECRACKER&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add berry blue jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup peach schnapps)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;31 &lt;em&gt;WHITE LIGHTNING&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add pina colada jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup triple sec)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;32&lt;em&gt;FUZZY NAVEL&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add 3 oz orange jello, 2 oz vodka, 6 oz peach schnapps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;33 &lt;em&gt;RED HEADED SLUT&lt;/em&gt; boil 1 cup water, add cranberry jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup peach schnapps, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup jager&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;34 &lt;em&gt;MOJITO&lt;/em&gt; (1 cup boiling water, 3 oz box lime jello, 6 oz white rum, 2 oz cold water. top with mint leaves chopped and crushed. (or substitue mint leaves with a splash of mint extract in the the boiling water.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35 &lt;em&gt;STRAWBERRY DAQUIRI&lt;/em&gt; (boil 1 cup water, add 3 oz package wild strawberry jello, 6 oz white rum, 1 oz sweet &amp;amp; sour or margarita mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;36 &lt;em&gt;DEVILS KISS&lt;/em&gt; 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 envelope of Knox Gelatin and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Goldschlager, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Bacardi-151. Stir well and wait until the liquid has cooled before pouring into jello shot cups. if you double up the Knox Gelatin in this one you can eliminate the cup serve these up as jigglers!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;37 &lt;em&gt;ANKLE BREAKER&lt;/em&gt; 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 envelope of Lime Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of 151 Rum, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Cherry Brandy. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;38 &lt;em&gt;FIRECRACKER 2&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Orange Jello and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Sloe Gin , and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Spiced Rum and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of 151 Rum. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;39 &lt;strong&gt;KOMANIWANALAYA&lt;/strong&gt; 2 cups of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Pineapple Jello and 1 box of Cranberry Jello (both 3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add 1 cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Amaretto, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of 151 Rum. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;40 &lt;em&gt;RAIN MAIN&lt;/em&gt; 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Orange Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Bacardi 151, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Melon Liqueur. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;41 ADAM AND EVE &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Lemon Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Brandy, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Pomogranate Liqueur and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Gin. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;42 ALABAMA SLAMMER &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 package of Lemon Jello (3 oz) and stir until everything is completely dissolved and then add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of coldwater. Next, add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Amaretto, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Southern Comfort, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Sloe Gin. Mix throuroughly until everything is well combined and the carefully pour into jello shot cups. Chill for 3 to 4 hours and serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43 ALL NIGHTER 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Cherry Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Watermelon Vodka. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;44 APPLE PIE 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cups ofboiling water. Dissolve 2 boxes of Lemon Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add 1 cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Light Rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Sweet Vermouth, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Apple Brandy and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofGrenadine. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;45 BANANA BOAT 1 cup of water. Dissolve 1 box of Pineapple Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Coconut Rum , and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofBanana Liqueur. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;46 BANANA SPLIT 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Strawberry Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofBanana Liqueur and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Creme de Cacao. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;47 BAT OUT OF HELL 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 package of Orange Jello (3 oz) and stir for at least 2 minutes until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Red Bull, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Rumand &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Blue Curacao. Stir until well combined and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;48 BERMUDA TRIANGLE 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Orange Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Spiced Rum and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Peach Schnapps. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;49 BLACK CAT 1 cup of boilingwater. Dissolve 1 package of Raspberry Jello (3 oz) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Black Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Chambord. Stir well and wait until the liquid is about room temperature before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;50 BLACK WIDOW 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 package of Grape Jello (3 oz) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Blackberry Vodka and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; teaspoon of Ginger Powder. Stir well and cool slightly before pouring into jello shot cups. For a schnazzy garnish, drop a singleblackberry in each cup before chilling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;51 COUGH DROP 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 3 oz package of Strawberry Jello and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Jagermeister. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;52 CRYPTINI 1 cup of HotCoffee. Dissolve 1 envelope of Knox Gelatin and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Iced Coffee, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Kahlua. Stir well and wait until the liquid has cooled before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;53 FRENCH TICKLER 1 cup of boilingwater. Dissolve 1 package of Orange Jello (3 oz) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Cinnamon Schnappsand &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka. Stir well and wait until the liquid has a chance to cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;54 HARVEY WALLBANGER 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 package of Orange Jello (3 oz) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofGalliano. Stir well until completely combined and wait until the liquid has cooled before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;55 JUICY FRUIT &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Pineapple Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofMelon Liqueur and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Peach Schnapps. Stir well and cool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;56 JAGERMASTER 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Orange Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Jagermeister, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Amaretto, and a just a splash of Grenadine. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;57 JAGERMONSTER 1 cup of boiling water . Dissolve 1 package of Orange Jello and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water , &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Jagermeister, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Grenadine. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;58 LETHAL INJECTION 2 cups of boiling water. Dissolve 1 package of Orange Jello (3 oz) and 1 package ofPineapple Jello (3 oz) and stir at least 2 minutes until completely dissolved. Add 1 cup of cold water followed by &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Amaretto, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Coconut Rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Dark Rum and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Spiced Rum. Stir well and wait until the liquid has cooled before pouring intojello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;59 LONG ISLAND ICED TEA and measure 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 2 packages of Lemon Jello (3 oz) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Cola and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water. Now get ready to add the alcohol - &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Gin, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of LightRum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Tequila. Stir until everything is well combined and let it cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;60 NINJA TURTLE 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Orange Jello and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Gin, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Blue Curacao. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;61 PAIN KILLER &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Pineapple Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Dark Rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofCoconut Rum and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Orange Liqueur. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;62 PIXIE STIX 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Lemon Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Southern Comfort, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Blackberry Brandy. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;63 RED SILK PANTIES 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Cranberry Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup ofPeach Schnapps. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;64 KINKY MALIBU BARBIE Boil 1 cup water, add peach jello, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Kinky Liquer, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Malibu Coconut Rum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;65 Killer Kool Aid 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cups of boiling water. Dissolve 2 boxes of Cranberry Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Gin, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Rum, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Chambord and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Triple Sec. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;66 Broken Heart 1 cup of boiling water . Dissolve 1 package of of Orange Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Vodka, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Chambord. Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;67 SCOOBY SNACKS 1 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 1 box of Pineapple Jello (3 oz size) and stir until fully dissolved. Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Melon Liqueur, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Coconut Rum . Stir well and cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;68 TIJUANA TAXI 2 cup of boiling water. Dissolve 2 packages ofLemon Jello (3 oz size) and stir at least 2 minutes until fully dissolved.Next, add 1 cup of cold water, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Tequila, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Blue Caracao and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of Tropical Fruit Schnapps. Stir until completely combined and give it a chance to cool before pouring into jello shot cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;69 RUMMY BEARS 1 cup boiling water, add any random flavor jello and 1 cup berry vodka, 1 gummy bear in the center of each shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;70 WOOWOO 2 cups boiling water, add 3 pkgs grape jello, 3 pkgs cranberry/raspberry jello, 3 pkgs strawberry jello, 3 cups vodka, 3 cups peach schnapps, 1 can grape juice concentrate and 1 can cran-raspberry juice concentrate (both undiluted!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
