<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>instant pot on Food for Thought</title>
    <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/tags/instant-pot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in instant pot on Food for Thought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/tags/instant-pot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Braised Pork Belly</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/braised-pork-belly/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ramen Eggs  1 cup Japanese soy sauce 1 piece kombu 1&amp;frasl;2 cup mirin 1&amp;frasl;2 cup cooking sake 1&amp;frasl;2 cup bonito flakes 1&amp;frasl;4 cup sugar 8 cloves garlic crushed 8 eggs  Braised beef  1 lb pork belly or shoulder, cut to 1&amp;frasl;3 in cubes 1 Tbsp vegetable oil 2 Tbsp shaoxing wine 3 Tbsp dark soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;4 cup fried shallots/onions 1 Tbsp garlic, chopped 2 star anise 2 dried shiitake mushrooms, soaked 1 stick cinnamon 2 Tbsp rock sugar or brown sugar 2&amp;frasl;3 cup hot water 10-15 dried chiles 2 Tbsp sichuan bean paste 3 tsp sambal olek 2 tsp chili crisp oil cornstarch  Directions Ramen Egg Boil a large pot of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Curry</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/japanese-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1-2 lb chicken 1 medium yellow onion, chopped 1 lb carrots 1.5 lb yukon gold potatoes 3 cups chicken stock (bullion works) 1 package curry cubes (~200g, I use &amp;ldquo;Golden Curry&amp;rdquo; brand) 1 Tbsp tomato paste (can use ketchup) 1 Tbsp soy sauce 3 cloves garlic  Optional additions:  1 apple, grated 1&amp;frasl;2 bar chocolate pinch of cheddar cheese 1 tablespoon honey  Directions Peel and chop potatoes in to 1&amp;frasl;2 inch cubes, put in a bowl with water to de-starch while doing next steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 lb beef stew meat 8 oz mushrooms 1 lb carrots 1.5 lb potatoes 14 oz bag frozen pearl onions 2 Tbsp flour 2 Tbsp butter 2 cups beef broth (bullion works) 1 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 Tbsp soy sauce 1&amp;frasl;2 Tbsp brown sugar 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 Tbsp tomato paste 1 tsp dried rosemary 1 tsp dried thyme Salt and pepper  Directions If stew beef is coarsely cut, further cut in to 1&amp;frasl;2-in cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shredded Chicken</title>
      <link>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nmwsharp.com/recipes/post/shredded-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbsp canola, vegetable or avocado oil 2 lbs boneless skinless chicken, cubed 1&amp;frasl;2 yellow onion, thinly sliced 4 cloves garlic, minced 1 tsp chili powder 1 tsp cumin 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp coriander 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp kosher sea salt 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp oregano juice of 2 oranges juice of 2 limes 1&amp;frasl;2 jalapeño, minced (or a whole pepper if you prefer slightly spicier) 1&amp;frasl;2 c. fresh cilantro  Directions Saute chicken with a small amount of oil and garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>